Anders G. Nordby



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Systems Architect and Senior Developer with 20+ years of experience designing scalable software solutions across industries. Specialized in application security, distributed systems, and modern architecture. Proven leader in team coordination, agile practices, and security governance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/2019 - PRESENT

Delichon AS

Systems Architect & Senior Developer

Customer: Element Logic **Duration:** 5 years

Roles: Senior Systems Developer, Security Champion

Technologies: C#, Akka.NET, Blazor, REST, GraphQL, NHibernate, SQL, NUnit, Moq, Microsoft .NET Standard, ASP.NET, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Git, Powershell, Kiuwan.

Responsibility: Senior developer on Element Logic's main product, eManager. Additionally, focuses on application security, and is the initiator and leader for Element Logic's Security Chapions Guild.

Customer: ABB

Role: Senior Systems Developer

Duration: 6 months

Technologies: Azure DevOps, Azure DB, Azure WebServices, Akka.NET, TypeScript, React JS, C#, Microsoft .NET Core, TFS, Git, Powershell.

01/2018 - 04/2019

Sopra Steria

Lead Software Engineer

Roles: In-house architect responsible for planning and QA of offers to customers. Senior developer for some customers.

Customers: Skatteetaten, Helsedirektoratet.

Technologies: C#, .Net, Episerver CMS, ASP.NET MVC, Microsoft SQL Server, JavaScript, Jira, Confluence, TFS, Git.

03/2014 - 08/2017

CGI

Senior Web Developer

Roles: Team Leader, Scrum Master, Hands-on Architect. Customers: ASKO, Fellesforbundet, Tekna, PIA, Miljødirektoratet. Technologies: C#, inRiver PIM, Apptus eSales, Episerver CMS, Episerver Commerce, IdentityServer, T-SQL, NServiceBus, Jira, Confluence, jMeter, BlazeMeter, Angular.js, Knockout.js.

03/2010 - 01/2014 08/2008 - 12/2009 02/2006 - 07/2008 10/2004 - 02/2008

05/1995 - 06/2002

Making Waves, Senior Systems Consultant Creuna, Consultant / Systems Developer Ocelluz, Systems Developer & Project Manager Anders Nordby Konsulenttjenester Ajilon, Consultant in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/agnordby/

(+47) 932 20 333

anders@delichon.no

Updated version of this dokument: https://github.com/agnordby/cv

Barcelona (One week pr month in Oslo)

KEY COMPETENCIES

Processes

Systems Architecture, Scrum, Kanban, Project Management.

Development

C#, Akka.Net, GraphQL, NHibernate, Blazor, Gherkin, Specflow, Cypress, NUnit, Moq, DoxFx, Docker, Swagger, Kiuwan, PowerBI, log4net, Episerver, ASP.Net, T-SQL, PL/SQL, Javascript, JSON, NServiceBus, REST, WebAPI, XML, HTML, CSS, Powershell, LATEX.

Tool

Jira, Confluence, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Git, TFS, SubVersion, NewRelic, jMeter, BlazeMeter, NuGet, Kiuwan.

CERTIFICATIONS

202I	Certified Optimizely Developer	
2020	Microsoft AZ900 Azure Fundamentals	
2019	PRINCE2 Practitioner	
2019	Certified Scrum Master	
2018	PRINCE2 Foundation	

COURSES

2024	Building an AppSec Scanning Programme
2019	Tom Gilb: Architecture Workshop
2018	Sopra Steria: Arkitekturskolen
2015	Microsoft: Lead Enterprise Architect Programme

EDUCATION

2003 – 2004	University of Oslo, Teacher Training
1999 – 2000	Oslo Business Academy, IT Candidate
1987 – 1996	University of Oslo, Cand.Mag.
1984 – 1987	Eikeli High School, Natural Sciences

AWARDS

2013-2017 Episerver Most Valued Professional

LANGUAGES

EXCELLENT	Norwegian (native), English
INTERMEDIATE	Bulgarian, German
BEGINNER	Spanish, Japanese